Eric Sentongo Kabugo

Stanley Ssekindi road, Muyenga, Kampala, Uganda
eric sentongo@yahoo.com
+256 759 961 228

Professional Summary

I am an accomplished software developer with 5+ years of experience. I excel in every stage of the software development life cycle, including analysis, design, coding, debugging, testing, deployment and maintenance. I devise innovative and tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of industries. I can learn new programming languages quickly when needed.

Skills

- Programming languages include C/C++/C#, Java, JavaScript, Python, PHP and MySQL.
- Other skills include HTML, CSS3, React JS, React Native, Redux, ES6, Node, Android

GitHub profile

https://github.com/r1z11

LinkedIn profile

https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-sentongo-5b17063a/

Website

https://buzinga.tk

Work Experience

Tech Support Intern (Rara InfoTech)

November 2011 - February 2012

- Upgrading and maintaining open source banking software.
- Collaborate with remote developers to fix bugs as they were discovered
- Train fellow staff to use the banking software
- Solve day to day technical issues in the workplace

Freelance Software Developer

2011 - present

- Developed a Classifieds website using PHP and MySQL and OsCommerce for Buzinga Classifieds (2011 - 2013)
- Developed Law Practice Management software using Qt, C++ and MySQL (2013 2018) https://github.com/r1z11/billboard
- Built an e-Commerce website for Trade Links Africa (2014 2015) using WordPress, Facebook SDK, PHP and MySQL
- Built several websites using HTML5, CSS3, React, PHP, MySQL and WordPress
- Created a Point of Sale application using Qt, C++, MySQL. Also implemented a Java and Derby version (2015 - 2016) https://github.com/r1z11/buzpos
- Built several Android applications (2014 2017) These apps include Bell Lager Shake and Win (app showcase video -https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nQtcRtyUGU4&t=100s), Airtel Data Geeks, Tubbaale ne Bell, Guiness and Tusker apps, Ug Mix Maestro
- Built an events React Native application for IOS and Android (2019 https://expo.io/@pulse35/fiid)
- Consulted on a number of projects for various companies like National Organic Movement of Uganda, Moving Ads Uganda and Oseon
- Fixed some hacked websites like https://dandhbeautv.co.ug/
- Mentored other developers.

Lead React Developer (RoundBob)

September 2018 - March 2019

- Implemented proposed application designs
- Developed an administrative dashboard using React JS
- Mentored a junior developer
- Worked as part of a team, with some members working remotely
- Built a React Native application for IOS and Android (https://expo.io/@es16297/roundbob)

Education

CISCO Certified Network Associate

2008 - 2009 Makerere University Kampala, Uganda

Bachelor of Computer Applications

2009 - 2012 Bangalore University, Garden City College Bangalore, Karnataka, India

C, C++ Certified programmer Aptech Java Smart Professional

2012 - 2013 Aptech Computer Education Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Advanced Diploma in Software Development

2015 - 2016 Aptech Computer Education Kampala, Uganda

Google's AR (Augmented Reality) Core

2018 coursera.org

Hobbies and Interests

When I am not sitting in front of a computer monitor, I like to disconnect and unwind in the great outdoors. My favorite activities include basketball, swimming, making art and crafts. And when i have to be indoors, i love to play some video games.